Institute of Fisheries Analysis fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Centre for Canadian Studies records, 1969 - 1991; F-240-5; 29 cm of textual records; Centre for Canadian Studies
  By 1978, the University had appointed a full-time director for the program. The director was advised by a Steering Committee with one member from each department in the University which offered courses acceptable for credit towards the minor in Canadian Studies. The Steering Committee also included representatives from the Faculty of Education, the library, and the Student Society.
  In 1980, the program was redesignated as the Centre for Canadian Studies, and offered students a major and honours in Canadian Studies. In addition, the Centre developed a French Canadian Studies Certificate Program.
  Upon the dissolution of the Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies in 1985, the Centre for Canadian Studies became part of the Division of Interdisciplinary Studies within the Faculty of Arts.
  Series includes records made and received by the Centre for Canadian Studies in the course of the general administration and organization of the Centre. Topics and activities covered include policies and procedures; committee formation and meetings; external review of the Centre; development, administration, and delivery of programs and courses; and the development of bilingual programs (predominantly in French). Document types include correspondence, meeting agendas and minutes, proposals, reports, statistics, and press clippings.
  Note that the records of the Institute of Fisheries Analysis contain university records from the Centre for Canadian Studies (CnS). As the records of CnS were so intermingled with the records of the IFA, the archivist decided to leave all records together in the IFA fonds. During arrangement and description the files and loose items, which were easily attributed to CnS, were separated from the other items and files, and assigned to a separate series within the fonds.
  For further information on this anomaly see the Institute of Fisheries Analysis (IFA) fonds notes, and scope and content.
  Centre for Canadian Studies
  For other material relating to the Centre for Canadian Studies, see the Centre for Canadian Studies fonds finding aid (F-64).
  - General administrative and subject files, 1978 - 1986; F-240-5-1; 4 cm of textual records
    Sub-series includes general administration and organization records of the Centre for Canadian Studies, as well as subject files on topics such as Simon Fraser University policies and procedures; faculty and academic appointments; budget; program development; visiting scholars; and seminars and workshops. Records predominantly consist of internal and external correspondence, memoranda, and notes.
    - [Memoranda], vol. 1, [ca 1978] - [ca 1986]; F-240-5-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - [Memoranda], vol. 2, [ca 1978] - [ca 1986]; F-240-5-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - MacKenzie, W.C., 1979 - 1980; F-240-5-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - [Correspondence - external], 1979 - [ca 1984]; F-240-5-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - [Associated faculty notes], 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - [Correspondence - internal], 1980 - 1984; F-240-5-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - [SFU policies and procedures - research and study groups], 1985; F-240-5-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
  - Committees, 1970 - 1991; F-240-5-2; 5 cm of textual records
    Records for this sub-series were made and received by various Centre for Canadian Studies committees, including the Undergraduate Curriculum Committee, Steering Committee, Graduate Studies Committee, and the Canadian Studies Review Committee (which is external to the Centre). Topics include academic programs and curricula; committee constitutions and mandates; and course scheduling. Records include minutes, correspondence, memoranda, and reports.
    Canadian Studies Steering Committee; Canadian Studies Undergraduate Curriculum Committee; Canadian Studies Graduate Studies Committee; Canadian Studies Review Committee
    - Canadian Studies Undergraduate Curriculum Committee, [197-?]; F-240-5-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - [Canadian Studies Undergraduate Curriculum Committee minutes], 1974 - 1983; F-240-5-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - Steering Committee - future business, 1978; F-240-5-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - Steering Committee constitution, 1978 - 1979; F-240-5-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - Steering Committee - current, 1978 - 1979; F-240-5-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - [Canadian Studies Steering Committee - minutes, notes, and memoranda], 1980 - 1986; F-240-5-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - Canadian Studies Graduate Studies Development Committee, 1983; F-240-5-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - [Canadian Studies Review Committee report], 1985 - 1986; F-240-5-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
    - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1990 - 1991; F-240-5-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 240-5)
  - Curriculum and instruction files, 1969 - 1991; F-240-5-3; 21 cm of textual records
    Records in this sub-series relate to various programs and courses developed and administered by the Centre for Canadian Studies. Topics covered include policies and procedures; committee formation and meetings; external review of the Centre; development, administration, and delivery of programs and courses; and the development of bilingual programs (predominantly in French). Document types include correspondence, meeting agendas and minutes, proposals, reports, statistics, and press clippings.
    - Curriculum and instruction - general files, 1978 - 1991; F-240-5-3-1; 5 cm of textual records
      - [Canadian Studies bibliography], [1978?]; F-240-5-3-1-1 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
        Creator's original file classification code: CN.S. 400.
      - [Canadian Studies 400: student hand-outs], [1978?]; F-240-5-3-1-2 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Canadian Studies 400: course administration, summer 1978], F-240-5-3-1-3 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Canadian Studies 400: course materials], 1978; F-240-5-3-1-4 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Canadian Studies 390/91-3], 1983; F-240-5-3-1-5 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Political Science 221], 1991; F-240-5-3-1-6 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
    - French language program files, 1977 - 1986; F-240-5-3-2; 9 cm of textual records
      - [Canadian Studies bilingual program - correspondence and memoranda], 1977 - 1980; F-240-5-3-2-1 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Canadian Studies bilingual program], 1979 - 1980; F-240-5-3-2-2 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Bilingual program], vol. 1, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-3 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Bilingual program], vol. 2, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-4 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Bilingual program - Centre for Studies in French], vol. 3, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-5 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Bilingual program], vol. 4, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-6 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Bilingual program], vol. 5, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-7 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - Bilingual program - processing of resubmission, vol. 6, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-8 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - [Bilingual program - current program], vol. 7, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-9 (Archival box - standard 240-6)
      - Bilingual program - Ministry of Education contacts, vol. 8, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-10 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Bilingual program], vol. 9, 1979 - 1985; F-240-5-3-2-11 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Program of studies in French - funding], [1980?] - [198-?]; F-240-5-3-2-12 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Program of studies in French - correspondence], 1985; F-240-5-3-2-13 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Program of studies in French - March 7, 1986 meeting papers], F-240-5-3-2-14 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
    - Programs and course proposals, 1969 - 1984; F-240-5-3-3; 7 cm of textual records
      - Canadian Studies program, 1969 - 1970; F-240-5-3-3-1 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - French Canadian Studies certificate program - planning, [197-]; F-240-5-3-3-2 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - German-Canadian Studies project, [197-]; F-240-5-3-3-3 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
        Open
      - Outside funding, [197-]; F-240-5-3-3-4 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - Bilingual program - planning, 1976 - 1977; F-240-5-3-3-5 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - Inventory of French medium instruction capabilities at Simon Fraser University, 1977 - 1979; F-240-5-3-3-6 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - Canadian Studies - news items of interest, 1978; F-240-5-3-3-7 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - Canadian Studies development plans, 1978; F-240-5-3-3-8 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - New major/honours proposal - internal processing, 1978 - 1979; F-240-5-3-3-9 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - Major program - new course proposals, 1978 - 1979; F-240-5-3-3-10 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - Proposed course offerings - current, 1978 - 1980; F-240-5-3-3-11 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - New major/honours proposal - external processing, 1979; F-240-5-3-3-12 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Proposal for a joint major between French and Canadian Studies], 1979; F-240-5-3-3-13 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Canadian Studies 400-3/401-3 - proposal], [ca 1980]; F-240-5-3-3-14 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Major/honours in Canadian Studies (SFU) - Universities Council letter], 1980; F-240-5-3-3-15 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Native Studies program], 1980; F-240-5-3-3-16 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [New course proposal], [ca 1980] - [ca 1981]; F-240-5-3-3-17 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      - [Canadian Studies program and enrolment], 1983 - 1984; F-240-5-3-3-18 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
- Department of Economics and Commerce records, 1960 - 1996; F-240-6; 91 cm of textual records; Department of Economics
  The Department of Economics and Commerce was established by the Board of Governors in February 1964, and began to offer courses within the Faculty of Arts leading to B.A., M.A., and Ph.D. degrees when the University opened in 1965. The Department was responsible, through its Head, for the promotion of research and the development and delivery of programs in the fields of economics and commerce.
  The Department expanded rapidly in size, growing from an initial 5 faculty members in 1965 to 52 in 1979. During this period it had greatly expanded its program offerings, including the important addition of a Master of Business Administration program in 1968. In September 1979 the Department underwent a re-organization, when it was subsumed by the new School of Business Administration and Economics in the Faculty of Arts. The School consisted of two departments: Business Administration and Economics. The School existed only until November 1981, when a separate Faculty of Business Administration was established. The Department of Economics has continued to exist in the Faculty of Arts.
  The Department was administered by a Chair and departmental committees, whose number and composition changed over time. The Chair was responsible for the overall administration of the Department, and reported to the Dean of Arts. In addition to its departmental committees, the Department adopted in 1969 a Constitution and By-laws for its Graduate Program in Economics. It stated that the Program would have three committees: the Graduate Studies Committee, the Curriculum Committee, and the Admissions Committee.
  Series includes records made and received by the Department of Economics and Commerce in the course of its development and administration. Activities and topics documented in the records include the establishment, organization, and operation of the department; development of department policies and procedures; committee formation and meetings; department publications and publicity; student, staff, and faculty relations; development, administration, and delivery of programs and courses; salary and tenure; scholarly activities of the department; and budget. The records primarily consist of correspondence, reports, meeting agendas and minutes, contracts, posters, brochures, publications, statistics, and press clippings.
  Note that the records of the Institute of Fisheries Analysis contain university records from the Department of Economics and Commerce (DEC). As the records of DEC were so intermingled with the records of the IFA, the archivist decided to leave all records together in the IFA fonds. During arrangement and description the files and loose items, which were easily attributed to DEC, were separated from the other items and files, and assigned to a separate series within the fonds.
  Department of Economics
  For other material relating to the Department of Economics and Commerce, see the Department of Economics fonds finding aid (F-8).
  - General administrative and subject files, 1960 - 1994; F-240-6-1; 38 cm of textual records
    Sub-series includes subject files, and general administration and organization records of the Department of Economics and Commerce. Topics and activities covered include faculty workloads, salary, and sabbatical; department development and promotion; program and project development and administration; department meetings; budgets; and scholarly activities. Record types include correspondence, memoranda, statistics, reports, policies, posters, brochures, newsletters, and contracts.
    - SFU final plan - architectural drawings, [196-?]; F-240-6-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
    - Individual faculty workloads, [196-?]; F-240-6-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
    - SFU administration, [after 1965]; F-240-6-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
      Creator's original file classification code: Administration.
    - [Faculty of Arts Graduate Studies Committee, [after 1965]; F-240-6-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
    - [Unified Economics and Commerce Department - notes], [after 1965]; F-240-6-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
    - DEC posters, [after 1965] - [ca 1977]; F-240-6-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
    - [Report on scholarly activities], vol. 1, 1965 - 1983; F-240-6-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
    - [Report on scholarly activities], vol. 2, 1965 - 1983; F-240-6-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 240-7)
    - For departmental discussion, 1966; F-240-6-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Salary data, 1966; F-240-6-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Salary defense, 1966; F-240-6-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Salary increments data, 1966; F-240-6-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Graduate academic program, 1966 - 1972; F-240-6-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Miscellaneous memoranda, vol. 1, 1966 - 1989; F-240-6-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Miscellaneous memoranda, vol. 2, 1966 - 1989; F-240-6-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - [DEC statistics], 1966 - 1989; F-240-6-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Special projects, 1967; F-240-6-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Department of Economics and Commerce Meetings, 1967 - 1968; F-240-6-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - [Information for DEC faculty], 1967 - 1969; F-240-6-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - DEC graduate studies program, enrolees, courses, faculty, 1967 - 1975; F-240-6-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - Petit affair, 1968; F-240-6-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
      Creator's original file classification code: Academic.
    - SFU faculty, vol. 1, 1968 - 1975; F-240-6-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 240-8)
    - SFU faculty, vol. 2, 1968 - 1975; F-240-6-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - [Department of Economics and Commerce Meetings], 1968; F-240-6-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - [Business Administration Division of the Department of Economics and Commerce - minutes, memorandum, proposed constitution, 1969; F-240-6-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - [Workshops and discussion papers], 1969; F-240-6-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - DEC department meeting, 1970; F-240-6-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - MBA administration, 1970; F-240-6-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - DEC Authorization, 1970; F-240-6-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - DEC administration, 1970 - 1971; F-240-6-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - Faculty Association, 1970 - 1971; F-240-6-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - Sabbatical policy, 1970 - 1971; F-240-6-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - [Department of Economics policies and procedures], 1970 - 1980; F-240-6-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - SFU reports and surveys, 1970 - 1982; F-240-6-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - DEC grades, course evaluations, 1971; F-240-6-1-0-35 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - [SFU Teachers' Committee on Indo-China], 1971; F-240-6-1-0-36 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - Faculty of Arts rules, 1971; F-240-6-1-0-37 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - DEC internal memos, 1971; F-240-6-1-0-38 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - Department Organization, 1971 - 1972; F-240-6-1-0-39 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - Academic matters - Faculty of Arts, 1971 - 1972; F-240-6-1-0-40 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - [Discussion papers - lists of], 1971 - 1982; F-240-6-1-0-41 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - [Pamphlet - SFU Department of Economics and Commerce evening masters degree program in economics], [ca 1972]; F-240-6-1-0-42 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - Travel budget, 1972; F-240-6-1-0-43 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - Instructor / assistant professor rank, 1972; F-240-6-1-0-44 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - Department discussion DEC chairmanship, 1972; F-240-6-1-0-45 (Archival box - standard 240-9)
    - [Department and University organization, policies, and procedures], vol. 1, 1972 - 1974; F-240-6-1-0-46 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - [Department and University organization, policies, and procedures], vol. 2, 1972 - 1974; F-240-6-1-0-47 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - [Department notes], 1972 - 1984; F-240-6-1-0-48 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - DEC brochures, [ca 1973]; F-240-6-1-0-49 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Regional Studies Journal, 1973; F-240-6-1-0-50 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Reports and surveys, 1974; F-240-6-1-0-51 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Correspondence - general, 1974 - 1985; F-240-6-1-0-52 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - ECCO - DEC student union newsletter, 1975 - 1976; F-240-6-1-0-53 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Graduate admissions materials, vol. 1, 1975 - 1984; F-240-6-1-0-54 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Graduate admissions materials, vol. 2, 1975 - 1984; F-240-6-1-0-55 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - DEC administration, 1977; F-240-6-1-0-56 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Registrar's office, 1977; F-240-6-1-0-57 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - [School notes], 1979 - 1980; F-240-6-1-0-58 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Contract - Newton, Christopher, 1980; F-240-6-1-0-59 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Work Study Program, 1984; F-240-6-1-0-60 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - [Department of Economics policies and procedures], 1986 - 1988; F-240-6-1-0-61 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - [Department of Economics seminars], 1989; F-240-6-1-0-62 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - [Department of Economics - faculty and staff list], 1991 - 1994; F-240-6-1-0-63 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
  - Committees, 1966 - 1983; F-240-6-2; 21 cm of textual records
    Records for this sub-series were made and received by various Department of Economics committees, including the Promotions and Salary Committee; Promotions and Tenure Committee; Joint Faculty Committee; Appointments Committee; Nominations Committee; Undergraduate Curriculum Sub-Committee; Executive Committee; Arts Appointment Committee; Economics Graduate Committee; Graduate Curriculum Committee; Dean’s Advisory Committee; Planning and Priorities Committee; and the President’s Advisory Committee in University Priorities. Topics and activities covered include salary and workload; promotions and tenure; faculty appointments; graduate and undergraduate program development; and budget. Document types include memoranda, correspondence, policies, surveys, minutes, and reports.
    Department of Economics. Promotions and Salary Committee; Department of Economics. Promotions and Tenure Committee; Department of Economics. Joint Faculty Committee; Department of Economics. Appointments Committee; Department of Economics. Nominations Committee; Department of Economics. Undergraduate Curriculum Committee; Department of Economics. Executive Committee; Department of Economics. Arts Appointment Committee; Department of Economics. Economics Graduate Committee; Department of Economics. Graduate Curriculum Committee; Department of Economics. Dean's Advisory Committee; Department of Economics. Planning and Priorities Committee; President's Advisory Committee on University Priorities
    - [Promotions and Salary Committee - promotions and salary increases], 1966; F-240-6-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - [Joint Faculty Committees], 1968; F-240-6-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Promotions and Tenure Committee - teaching survey, 1968 - 1970; F-240-6-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 240-10)
    - Appointments Committee, vol. 1, 1968 - 1971; F-240-6-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Appointments Committee - Faculty budget 1970/71, vol. 2, 1968 - 1971; F-240-6-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Appointments Committee - decisions, vol. 3, 1968 - 1971; F-240-6-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Nominations Committee, 1968 - 1972; F-240-6-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - [Undergraduate Curriculum Sub-Committee report], [ca 1969]; F-240-6-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Promotions and Tenure Committee, vol. 1, 1969 - 1970; F-240-6-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Promotions and Tenure Committee, vol. 2, 1969 - 1970; F-240-6-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Executive Committee - Meetings, 1970; F-240-6-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Executive Committee, vol. 1, 1970 - 1971; F-240-6-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Executive Committee, vol. 2, 1970 - 1971; F-240-6-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Executive Committee - Minutes, 1970 - 1971; F-240-6-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Nominations Committee, 1970 - 1971; F-240-6-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Promotions and Tenure Committee, vol. 1, 1971; F-240-6-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Promotions and Tenure Committee, vol. 2, 1971; F-240-6-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 240-11)
    - Arts Appointments Committees, 1971; F-240-6-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 240-12)
    - SFU promotion and tenure, 1971; F-240-6-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 240-12)
    - Appointments Committee, 1971; F-240-6-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 240-12)
    - Workload, 1971 - 1972; F-240-6-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 240-12)
    - Economics Graduate Committee, 1971 - 1972; F-240-6-2-0-22 (Archival box - standard 240-12)
    - Promotions and Tenure Committee - General, 1971 - 1972; F-240-6-2-0-23 (Archival box - standard 240-12)